This is the grave I've chosen for Shilang
여기가 내가 석랑을 위해 고른 무덤이다
This place is called Tiannan Pass
이곳 이름은 천남관이라고
Composed of two peaks, east and west
동서 두 산봉우리로 조성되었는데
Adjacent to Tianhe
천하를 끼고 있고
Only one narrow path in between for troops to pass
가운데 행군할 수 있는 작은 길이 한 개 있어
If a large army marches here
대군은 여기까지 오면
They will inevitably form a long line
긴 대열을 이뤄야 해서
Front and rear cannot support each other
앞뒤가 서로 돕지 못해
We only need
적을 이곳으로
To lure the enemy here
유인하기만 하면 돼
The vanguard
전방 병력은
Will block Shilang
석랑을 막고
The rear guard will take the mountain paths
후방 병력은 산골짜기 사이 작은 길로
In groups to encircle from behind
여러 조로 나뉘어 뒤로 가되
If we encounter enemy troops
적군을 만나면
Don't engage
얽혀 싸우지 말고
Just disperse them
쫓아서 흩어지게 해
And I
그리고 난
Will set the central camp on the mountain
중군 대영을 산에 세운다
After Shilang's main force is attacked
석랑의 주력은 습격당하면
They will surely flee along the mountain paths
산골짜기 사이 작은 길로 뿔뿔이 도망칠 거야
At that time
그러면
I will personally lead the central army to intercept the fleeing enemy
내가 중군을 이끌고 도망치는 적을 무찌르겠다
This battle
이번엔
Must completely annihilate their 50,000 main force
꼭 그들의 15만 주력군을
Completely
몽땅 섬멸해야 한다
In this way
그리하면
Shi Wei's so-called 180,000 army
석위가 말하는 80만 대군은
Will scatter like birds and beasts
뿔뿔이 흩어지고
The Central Plains can be pacified
중원은 안정될 것이야
The task of luring the enemy is very dangerous
적을 유인하는 임무는 아주 위험하다
Who is willing to be the vanguard?
누가 선봉을 맡겠느냐
Father
부황
You can't catch a wolf without risking the child
호랑이 굴에 들어가야 호랑이 새끼를 잡는다고
Your son is willing to be the vanguard
소자가 선봉을 맡겠습니다
Good
좋다
I'll give you a unit of elite cavalry
정예 기병을 줄 테니
To lure Shilang's main force into the pass
석랑의 주력을 유인해라
Yes
네
Halt
서라
Who goes there?
누구냐
They say Wuzhao people are brave and skilled
오노들은 용맹하고 싸움에 능하다는데
How
오늘
How come all I see today are cowards?
내가 만난 것들은 왜 하나같이 겁쟁이냐
Everyone inside, listen
안에 사람들은 들으라
Who dares come out and fight me?
나와서 나랑 한판 붙자
Young General
소장군
General Shilang said
석랑 장군이
No one is to go out and fight
절대 싸움에 응하지 말랬어요
To hell with that
다 집어치워
I'll kill this brat first
저놈부터 죽이고 볼 판이야
Young General
소장군
Report
아룁니다
Shilang's army is moving
석랑 대군이 움직입니다
Good, the Second Prince is brave
잘됐네요 이황자의 위풍 덕입니다
If Shilang wants to maintain morale
석랑은 사기를 위해서라도
He will surely follow
꼭 나와서 싸울 겁니다
Zu Yue
조월
Lead your troops
자네가 병마 3만을 끌고
To face the Second Prince head-on
정면으로 둘째를 맞이해서
Fight while retreating
싸우면서 퇴각하게
Your servant
소신
Receives the order
명 받잡겠습니다
Zhu Yuanzhi
주원지
Half an hour after Shilang's main force enters the pass
석랑의 주력이 입관 반 시진 후
Lead the ambush troops to attack
복병을 이끌고 출격하여
Block Shilang's army's retreat
석랑 대군의 퇴로를 끊어라
Your servant receives the order
소신 명 받잡겠습니다
Brat, give me back my son's life
이놈아 내 아들 목숨 내놔
Bad, there's an ambush
큰일 났어요 매복입니다
Kill
죽여라
Kill them
다 죽여라
Report
아룁니다
Shilang's army has all entered the pass
석랑 대군이 몽땅 좁은 길에 들어왔습니다
Shilang discovered he's surrounded
석랑은 포위된 걸 알고
Instead of retreating, he advances
후퇴는커녕 전진하며
Sending heavy armor to break through
중갑군으로 밀어붙여
One charge has broken through two lines
이미 방어선 두 개를 뚫었습니다
They know they're ambushed
매복이 있는 걸 알면서
Yet still lead the army deeper
더 깊숙이 들어오다니
Report
아룁니다
Minister Li Dingyuan
이정원 대인이
Sent an urgent message from the rear
빠른 말로 후방 급보를 전해왔습니다
Your Majesty
폐하
Some are planning rebellion
정변 조짐이 있답니다
Minister Li says
이대인이 그러는데
Many gentry believe this battle is hopeless
사족들은 우리가 패한다고 생각하고
And are stirring panic in the rear
후방에서 공황을 선동한대요
The Chen and Xie families
진가와 사가가
Will handle it
잘 처리할 것이야
Your Majesty
폐하
But the Chen family head
허나 진가의 가주는
Is now the Second Prince's mother
이황자의 모비입니다